<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pascal de Vink</title>
        <link></link>
        <description>RSS feed for Pascal de Vink</description>
        <atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <item>
                <title>Imposter!</title>
                <description><![CDATA[<p>Next month I'll be turning 30.</p>

<p>I don't feel old though. I've been bald for a couple of years, so that won't bother me anymore. Since I was diagnosed with diabetes a couple of years ago, I can't stand too much alcohol, so I won't be suffering much more in the weekends than I already am (when drunk). In fact, I don't feel 30. I still <em>feel</em> young. Not 18 young, I am smart enough to notice I'm not 18 anymore, but somehow I don't feel like I'm 30 years old. I just act like it sometimes. I pretend to be grown up. I'm an imposter.
And sometimes I'm afraid that people might find out and call me out on it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>So here I am<br />
  Growing older all the time<br />
  Looking older all the time<br />
  Feeling younger in my mind<br />
  -- Goldfinger, <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/6cL7NCFSvqWrBH5r4mkvVV">Superman</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>It's not that I don't want to grow up. I'm not suffering from Peter Pan syndrome. It's just that I don't feel like I'm the real deal. Like there's a younger version trapped inside me who desperately tries to pretend being grown up, just to avoid being called out on it. Some of the times it can feel mighty overwhelming. The pressure of being an adult, of not falling out of line. As if the entire world would be against me if they'd discover the truth. As if nobody would ever take me serious ever again. As if a tribune of good and brave adults is going to judge me.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>"My friends say I should act my age<br />
  What's my age again?<br />
  What's my age again?"<br />
  -- Blink 182, <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/1hWrl3T1kIH5b9zRHLfCOn">What's My Age Again</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I recently read <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/1455581089">The Art Of Asking by Amanda Palmer</a> (thanks <a href="http://twitter.com/skoop">@skoop</a> for the gift!) and she calls it "the fraud police" (she talks in depth about it in her book and in short in this commencement speech: https://vimeo.com/24405060).<br />
She describes it like this: "The fraud police are this imaginary, terrifying force of experts and real grown-ups who don't exist and who come knocking on your door at 3am when you least expect it, saying 'Fraud police! We've been watching you and we have evidence that you have no idea what you are doing and you stand accused of the crime of completely making shit up as you go along. You do not actually deserve your job and we're taking everything away and we're telling everybody'."</p>

<p>And that is exactly how I feel.</p>

<p>Even worse, it's not only about feeling like an imposter as an adult, but as an imposter in my job.<br />
My job title says I'm a Lead Developer. But more often then not, It feels like I make it up as I go and have no clue what I'm talking about. How can I be the Lead Developer if I don't even know what the hell I'm talking about!? In the developer community, this is known as Imposter Syndrome. As a starting developer the world was my oyster and I felt like I could take on the entire world with my newly found skills. Given enough time of course. Fast forward a couple of years and I feel like I haven't even scratched the surface of all there is to know as a developer.</p>

<p>As one of the organisers of AmsterdamPHP (a pretty successful PHP user group in Amsterdam * duh *), I come into contact with a lot of great people. And almost every time I'm blown away by everything I don't know yet. And if that's not enough, when I finally catch up a couple of weeks or months later, it turns out the world moved on and there's something else to learn and know. Like I said: I might be a Lead Developer in title, but I make stuff up as I go, hoping I know where to look or who to ask if things get really messy.</p>

<p>And that is basically it. I haven't come to grips with the fact that it's ok to not know everything and I sure still feel like I'm faking it. But at least I know I can ask people for help. And I think building a network of people around you who can be relied on is a good step in that direction. User groups like <a href="http://www.amsterdamphp.nl">AmsterdamPHP</a> and great community events such as <a href="http://www.weca.mp">WeCamp</a> are a great help in achieving both goals. Being able to get to know people who know more than I do and getting mentored for personal growth are invaluable things I've gained in the last couple of years.</p>
]]></description>
                <link>/personal/2015/03/07/imposter/</link>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 00:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
                <guid>/personal/2015/03/07/imposter/</guid>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>
